Guide to the Dept. of Textiles and Apparel records, 1942-2005.
Dept. of Textiles and Apparel records, 1942-2005
- Series IV. Newsletters and Publications
  - F. TXA Publications
    - Keeping Clothes Wearable: Mending Clothing and Household Fabrics, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Author: Butt, Glady's
    - Keeping Customers Satisfied, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Author: Zetocha, Dale
    - Keeping Warm and Safe, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Kit Information Notes, no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Knit Fabrics Terms, no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Knit Picking- The Interlocks, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Knit Sport Jacket, no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Author: Mclean, Jean and Blum, Madeline
    - Knitted Apparel and Fabrics, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Knitted Fabrics, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Knitting, no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Laundering Baby's Clothing, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Laundering Without Phosphates, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Author: Purchase, Mary and Warner, Gret
    - Laundry Game, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Layman's Guide to "Lycra" Spandex Fiber, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Learn to Sew T-1- Leader's Suggestion Sheet, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Learning About Fibers and Yarns, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Leather and Suede, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Blouses, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Blouses and Shifts, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Costume Coordinates, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Let's Buy Skirts, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Author: Conklyn, Nancy
    - Let's Sew Series, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Series Program Materials, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Let's Sew Skirts, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letter to 4-H Cooperative Extension Agents, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Author: Focht, Brenda; McLean, Jean; Blum, Madeline
    - Linen, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lining a Tailored Garment, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - List of Tailoring Technique Samples, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Look What's Happened to Thread, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Author: Estes Berg, Shirley
    - Lycra Spandex Fiber, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Machine Quilting, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Make Bike Ankle Straps, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Make It Fashion-Right with Ramie, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Author: Banwart, Flo
    - Make Your Furs Wear Longer, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Author: Butt, Gladys
    - Make-Over Magic, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Making Shirts For the Men of the Family, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Market Fundamentals for the Small Home Business, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Marketing Strategies, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Author: Wotherspoon, Beverly
    - Marketing Worksheet, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Marking Your Fabric: The Dressmaking Series, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Matching the Fabric to the Pattern and Person- Leader's Guide, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Maximize Your Profits Through Pricing, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Author: Greenhalgh, Nile
    - Media Services Packet, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Memorandum, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Men's and Boy's Hip-Go-Round, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mending Clothes and Household Fabrics, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Minute-and-a-Half Patch, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mitered Corner, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mitten Magic, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Montgomery County 4-H Clothing Program Outline, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Montgomery County 4-H Clothing Program Overview, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Multilith Production Order, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - My Quiet Book, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Author: Futtrup, Mary
    - Necklines With Ribbing and Self-Fabric Trims, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New Dimensions in Stretch Fabrics, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New Fashions From Yesterday's Clothes, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New Poromeric Fabric for Skiwear, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New Program Opportunities with Singer Company (letter), no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New Third Generation Protective Clothing from High Performance Fibers--from Knives to Bullets, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Author: Kirkland, Kevin
    - New Washable From the World of Chemistry, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New York Times/CBS News Poll Summary, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - North American Rayon Carbonized Fiber, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Author: Looney, Robert
    - Northeast Clothing Leaders Guide- Level II Committee Metting (Memorandum), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Notes, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Organizing at the Sewing Machine, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Organizing Your Sewing Center, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pants: Fashion & Fit, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pants: Fashion and Fit Kit, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pattern Alteration and Fitting, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pattern Alteration Worksheet, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pattern Alteration Worksheet- With Numbers, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pattern Alteration- Armhole Large for Sleeve, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Armhole- Small/Large, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Bodice Back Narrow/Wide, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Bust Tight/Loose, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Chest Too Wide, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Gaping Armhole, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- High Hip, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Hip- Tight/Loose, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Hollow Chest, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Neckline Gaps, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Round Shoulders, Dowager's Hump, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Round Tummy, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Shoulder Seams Short/Long, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Sleeve Cap Short/long, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Sleeve Tight/Loose, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Square/Sloping Shoulders, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Sway Back, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Alteration- Waist Tight/Loose, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Fitting and Alteration-Compilation, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Picking for 4-H Clothing Level 1, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Picking for 4-H Clothing Level 2, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Selection for Children, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Author: Snellman, Adaline
    - Pattern Selection Sheet for Intermediate Sewers, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pattern Selection Sheet for New Sewers, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Patterns for Sewing Equipment, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Perky Pockets, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Phosphates and Detergents in Water Pollution, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Author: Purchase, Mary
    - Placing a Shirt Patterm on Plaid Fabric, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Planning a Garment of Plaid Fabric, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Planning For Short-Cut Sewing, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Polyporpylene- The Hi Tech Fiber, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Poncho, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Preparation of Fitting Dress, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Prequilted Fabrics, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pressing Equipment, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Author: Adams, Constanc
    - Pressing in Dressmaking, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pricing Your Product, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Pricing Your Service, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Problem Areas: What To Do With Bulk, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Problems Involved in the Exhibition, Care, and Handling of Space Suits, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Author: Kozloski, Lillian
    - Procrastination, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Progress Report on Ramie, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Publicizing Your Business, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Putting it All Together- Leader's Guide, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Questions and Answers About Polyester Double Knits, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Quilted fabrics, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Rain Protection, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Author: Warner, Gret
    - Rain/Wind Wear, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Rainwear for casual Protection- The Water Repellent Way!, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Ramie-Friend or Foe?, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Rayon-The Great Imitator, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Reading References for Tailoring, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Recordkeeping Guide, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Author: Davis, Susan and Gotwals, Lois
    - Recycle Your Wardrobe, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Recycled Place Mats, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Recycling Patterns, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Reference Sources on Fitting Pants, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Resources Available for Teaching Pattern Fitting and Alteration, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Restitch and Renew to Keep Clothes in Use, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Author: Kahabka, Bernetta
    - Reteaching Ideas, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Role of Clothing and Children in the Development for Children, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Author: Smart
    - Save Time Hemming Slacks or Trousers, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: Schmidt, Barbara
    - Seam Finishes, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Securing a Loan and Preparing a Business Plan, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Selecting Good Quality Fabric- Questions and Answers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sew for Growth: Lesson Guide, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: Snellman, Adaline and Blum, Madeline
    - Sew Smart with Sheets, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sewing For Children, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sewing Lightweight, Tightly-Woven Fabrics- Tafeta, Cire, Chambray, Ripstop, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sewing Made Easy, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: McLean, Jean
    - Sewing Tafeta, Cire, Chambray, and Ripstop, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sewing with Fake Suede, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sewing with Stripes, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: Futrell, Eloise
    - Shoppers Handbook: Labeling, Fabric Facts, Clothing Care, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: Blum, Madeline and Mclean, Jean
    - Short-Cut Closures, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Gathering, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Hems, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Pockets, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Preparation, Layout, Cutting, and Marking, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Tricks, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Short-Cut Waistbands, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Shoulder Pads and Shapes, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Silk- A New Future, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Simplified Sewing Series: 1 (Sleeves), no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Simplified Sewing Series: 2 (Collars & Cuffs), no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sleeping Bags, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sleeves and Plackets, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Small Companies Fill Specific Needs, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Author: Shaeffer, Claire
    - So Sew: Altering Ready-to-Wear, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - So Sew: Fly-Front Zipper Closing, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - So Sew: Personalizing Techniques, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - So Sew: Tips on Zippers, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Soaps and Other Detergents, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Williamson, Lucile
    - Soaps and Water Softeners, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Soft Fibers, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Some "Interviewing Pointers", 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Yerka, Bettie Lee
    - Some Alterations for Figure Variations, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Sources of Advice and Counseling, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stain Removal, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Lemley, Ann and Purchase, Mary
    - Stains That Land Clothes in the Trash, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Start With a Good Fitting Pattern, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Starting a Business in Your Home- Is it for You?, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - State In-Service Education- 4-H, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stitching Problems- Questions and Answers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Storage of Sewing Supplies, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Cooperm L. Leola
    - Straightening Fabrics for Home Sewing, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stretch Fabrics, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stretch Knit Velours and Terrys, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stretchology, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Suggested Guidelines for Clothing Levels, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Suggested References- History of Costume, Role of Women, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tailored Collars, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tailoring Techniques In-Service, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tailoring Techniques Teaching Kit, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Taking Accurate Body Measurements, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Techniques Used in Altering Patterns, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Test Date for Urethane Coated Fabrics, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Textile Comfort Features, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Textile Update, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Textiles, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Textiles and Clothing Program Guide, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Textiles Skills for 4-H Clothing Level 1, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The 4-H Clothing Handbook, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Young, Frances and Jamba, Barbara
    - The Big Detergent Question, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Purchase, Mary E.
    - The Care of Your Clothes…Home Laundry, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Feather, Betty and Caselman, Marilyn
    - The Denim Block Technique, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Diaper Dilemma (Laundry), no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Laundry System, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Purchase, Mary and Lemley, Ann
    - The Laundry System: Fabric, Soil, Supplies, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Author: Purchase, Mary and Wiegand, Elizabeth
    - The Retailer: The Custom Dressmaker's Personal Pipeline to the Homesewing Industry, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Role of the Dart in Fitting, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Welt or Stand Pocket, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Thread Update, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tips for Sewing on Fake Fabric, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - To Finish or Miter the Corner of a Fabric, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - To-Days Social Concerns, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Today's Sewing Machine Needles- Questions and Answers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Today's Thread- Questions and Answers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Triangular Head Scarf, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tricky Tabard, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tris- Frequently Asked Questions, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tris-Treated Children's Sleepwear, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Ultrasuede, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Understanding Soil Removal from Textiles and Apparel, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Unlimited "Stick-Toitiveness", no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - V-Necks for Knits, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Vinyl House Siding, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Waistband-- Covered Belting, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Waistband-- Self-Covered, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Wash and Wear, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Author: Blum, Madelin
    - Ways You and Your Club Can Help Disabled Persons, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Welt Pocket With a Flap- Open Window Method, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - What Clothing Means to Your Child, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Author: Hower, Donna
    - What Pants Pattern to Buy?, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Wheelchair Bag, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Who Am I?, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Wondrous Wool, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Wool Skirt, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Wool Techniques, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - You and Your Sewing Machine, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Your Home Demonstration Program Means Opportunity, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Your Sewing Helpers, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Your Sewing Twin- The Dress Form, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Zippered Shoulder Bag, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Series V. Reports
  - A. Annual
    - Annual report: Department of Textiles and Clothing, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - TXA annual report, 1970-1971; 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - TXA annual report, 1976-1977; 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - TXA annual report, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - TXA annual report, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - TXA annual report and salary recommendations, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - TXA annual report, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - TXA annual report, 1983-1984; 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - TXA annual report, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - TXA annual report, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - TXA annual report, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - B. Extension-TXA
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1942-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Department of Textiles and Clothing: extension annual reports, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - C. Faculty Annual Reports
    See additional faculty reports in electronic format in collection #23-2-2817
    - Ashdown, Susan, 1991-2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Breen, Nancy, 1987-2002 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Chu, Chin-Chang, 1980-2003 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Coffman, Charlotte, 1989-2003 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Darling,Susan, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - DiTella, Katrie, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Jirousek, Charlotte, 1992-2003 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Kozen, Frances, 1995-2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Lemley, Ann, 1981-2007 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Loker, Suzanne, 1998-2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Netravali, Anil, 1987-2003 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Obendorf, S. Kay, 1980-2004 (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
    - Racine, Anita, 1971-2012 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Schwartz, Peter, 1984-2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Van Dyke, Lewis, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - D. Various Reports
    - "Recommendations of an Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Textiles and Clothing in a Reorganized College", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Guide to the Cornell Costume Collection, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Proposal to establish a PhD Degree in Textile Science in the Field of Design and Environmental Analysis., 1985-03 (Box 1, Folder 5A)
    - TXA evolution of the department, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Program resources and visual and demonstration aids and study packets, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 4-H survey on youth programming in textiles and apparel, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Summary of Review of Graduate Program in the Field of Textiles" prepared by Peter Schwartz and Kay Obendorf., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - TXA strategic plan, December 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - External review, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - TXA lending library, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series VI. Subject Files
  - Definition TXA, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Department split, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department review, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - PhD proposal-background information, 1965-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - TXA apparel design program consultation, 1989-06 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CSRS review, 1994-04 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Protective Clothing for Youth-Watkins (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Helen Bull Vandervort Alumni Achievement Award, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Reclassification to Extension Associate I, July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Apparel Textile Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Institute, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Institute, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American Association for Textile Technology, Inc. (AATT): documents and photograph, 1979; 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AATT charter, bylaws, student awards, February 1967; 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - AATT member lists, photographs, Cornell student chapter information (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Agent/faculty meeting notes (TXA), October 1987; May 1988,; October 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cooperative extension programs in TXA (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative extension (TXA) meeting notes, 1987-10-1991-11 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Textiles and Apparel faculty (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Undergraduate education: resident instruction, misc. photographs of TXA students (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Undergraduate education, research, and graduate education (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Graduate research position, TXA publicity (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Graduate student projects, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Student guide-TXA/DEA, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Undergraduate admissions/TXA recruitment materials (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Graduate field information, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - TXA-policy and procedure manual, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Design League publicity flyers, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Consortium for Apparel Research, Education and Training (CARET), 1992-1994-08 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Consortium for Apparel Research, Education and Training (CARET), 1994-09-1994-11 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Consortium for Apparel Research, Education and Training (CARET), 1994-12-1995-01 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Consortium for Apparel Research, Education and Training (CARET), 1995-02-1995-05 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Consortium for Apparel Research, Education and Training (CARET), 1994-09-1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - CARET - Cornell resources (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Extension associate position, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - New York State apparel industry, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Summer research fellowship, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Corporate development - Center for Manufacturing Enterprise Policy Board, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - American Textile Partnership (AMTEX) information, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Conflicts oversight process, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - SUNY approval of department name change, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Series VII. Audiocasette Tapes
  - Mary Purchase--tr.7767a, 1989-08; tr.7767a
  - Anita Racine: "Dresses: A Reflection of Women's Roles", 1990-10-06; tr.7768a
  - Kay Obendorf; "Ring Around the Collar", 1982-12; tr.10853 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Series VIII. Projects and Proposals
  - Extension project proposals, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Proposal - extension program for apparel industry, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Student project - Da'Spot Clothing Store, Ithaca, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Southern Tier industrial technology extension pilot program, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Proposal for a center for apparel science and technology, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Proposal for a center for advanced technology, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series IX. Graduate Programs
  - MPS in apparel design, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PhD in fiber science, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PhD in fiber science, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - PhD in apparel design, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Changing name of graduate field to Fiber Science and Apparel Design, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series X. Publicity
  - Publicity, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Publicity, 1996-2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)